# SANDEEP SUMAN

## ASSISTANT MANAGER

I am an Electrical Engineer as well as Renewable Energy student Interested to utilise my technical knowledge with good Managerial skill; seeking a position to utilise my skills and abilities in the industries that offers professional growth while being resourceful, innovative and flexible. Assistant Manager with experience providing leadership necessary for sales growth and increased profit margin. Cultivates open communication with employees and provides feedback to improve job performance. Motivated Project manager with demonstrated knowledge of mining and manufacturing best practices and operations. Proven skills in enhancing productivity, efficiency and bottom-line profits with forward-thinking leadership. Bringing 6 years of experience in field and ready to take on challenging, growth-oriented role with Central Coalfields Limited.

### Contact

#### **Address**

C/O BRIJENDRA KUMAR,
PLOT NUMBER- 135, B KH NO.61/6, G/F, BLOCK-C,
SULTANPUR ROAD,
ANANDPUR
New Delhi, DL 110081

### **Phone**

+91-8092997359

#### E-mail

sandeep.suman@terisas.ac.i n

### LinkedIn

sandeep.suman@terisas.ac.i n

#### **Twitter**

sandeepkgp16@gmail.com

## Skills

While at university I have developed a number of other skills. Leadership skills while representing my year,

# **Work History**

Current

2013-03

# 2013-03 - Assistant Manager (Electrical & Mechanical)

COAL INDIA LIMITED, RANCHI, JHARKHAND

- Worked also as Project Engineer (E&M)
- Recruited and retained top talent, with focus on completing timely performance evaluations, providing positive feedback and rewarding superior performance
- Trained team members in successful strategies to meet operational and sales targets
- Supported staff development and goal attainment by focusing on skill development and job satisfaction
- Provided current employees options for additional training opportunities
- Managed opening and closing procedures and recommended changes to enhance efficiency of daily activities

# 2010-07 - Electrical Engineer

K YATNESH ENGINEERING CONSULTANCY, BIRATNAGAR, MORANG, NEPAL

- Conducted material tests and analysis using Electro -Mechanical equipment and tools
- Worked closely with engineers, land surveyors and other key stakeholders on different infrastructure projects

which also required me to communicate accurate information to course members and years heads. I also gained managerial as well as technical skills to handle situation and people in my present working area.

/	9
Electrical Engineering	Excellent
Leadership skills	Excellent
Managerial	••••0 Very Good
Seminars	Excellent
Staff management	Excellent
Issue resolution	Very Good
Employee performance evaluations	Very Good
Strategic planning	••••O Very Good
Employee scheduling	••••0 Very Good
Project management	Excellent
Operations management	Excellent
Contract Management	Very Good

Sales growth

Very Good

- Provided technical guidance, peer review and mentorship to junior engineers engaged in building system designs
- Led project scheduling and budgeting to successfully and quickly complete engineering projects

### **Education**

# 2018-07 - M. Tech: RENEWABLE ENERGY ENGINEERING AND Current MANAGEMENT

TERI University - Delhi South

- Continuing education in Renewable Energy Engineering and Management
- Minored in Energy Audit
- Dissertation: Energy Saving Measures in different Industries in BIRATNAGAR, NEPAL
- Member of Organiser Renewable Energy Symposium REtopia-2019

# 2006-07 - Electrical Engineering

2010-07

Kalyani Government Engineering College - Kalyani

- Graduated with 7.62 GPA
- Minored in Electric Overhead Trolley, TATA Steel Jamshedpur, Jharkhand, India
- Majored in NTPC BADARPUR DELHI
- Modelling presentation of a Wind turbine

# Certifications

- 1. Went for a four weeks Vocational training at TATA STEEL JAMSHEDPUR.
- 2. Four weeks Vocational training at NTPC BADARPUR, DELHI.
- 3. Seminar on "POWER SCINARIO IN BIHAR".
- 4. E-tendering and project engineer work for more than two years.
- 5. Attended Seminars & Expo in renewable Energy Fields. Organised REtopia-19

Staff
supervision

Excellent

Financial ••••
management Very Good

Cost control Very Good

# Languages

English

Hindi

Bangla

Maithili

# **Interests**

Required Internship or working profile in Renewable energy fields starting from January 2020 on wards...

Solar Photo Voltaic Projects

Sustainable Development

Electric Mobility

Energy Efficiency

Fuel Cell

LITHIUM ION BATTERY

Smart Grid

## **Software**

RET screen

Excellent

PVsyst

Very Good

SAM

Very Good

Homer

Very Good

# **Accomplishments**

- Promoted to Key Holder after only 16 months of employment
- Collaborated with team of 250 in the development of Asia Largest Project Magadh-Amrapali Area
- Supervised team of 24 staff members